距離地球600公里處  溫度波動在125℃至-100℃
聲音不能傳播
沒有氣壓
沒有氧氣
太空中生命無法存活
地      心      引      力
請確認置換蓋第一和第二部分
Please verify that the P-one ATA removal
P1 ATA資料已刪除
on replacement cap part one and two are complete.
記憶體中M1  M2  M3  M4均已刪除
DMA M-one, M-two, M-three and M-four are complete.
收到  探索者
Okay. Copy that, Explorer.
斯通博士  這裡是休士頓
Dr. Stone, Houston.
醫護組擔心你的心電數值
Medical is concerned about your ECG readings.
我很好  休士頓
I'm fine, Houston.
醫護組可不這麼想  博士
Well, Medical doesn't agree, Doc.
感到噁心嗎
Are you feeling nauseous?
和平時一樣  休士頓
Not any more than usual, Houston.
體征檢測正常
Diagnostics are green.
聯接通信卡  準備資料接收
Link to communications card ready for data reception.
如果一切順利  我明天回去
If this works, when we touch down tomorrow,
請你們大家喝酒
I'll buying all you guys a round of drinks.
說定了  博士
That's a date, Doctor.
記住  休士頓最愛瑪格麗塔
Just remember, Houston's partial to margaritas.
啟動通信卡
Booting comms card now.
請確認
Please confirm link.
通信失敗  我們沒收到資料
That's a negative, we're not seeing any data.
稍等  休士頓  我重啟一下通信卡
Standby, Houston, I'll gonna reboot the comms card.
待命
Standing by.
休士頓  我對這次任務有種不祥的預感
Houston, I have a bad feeling about this mission.
仔細說說
Please expand.
好的  我給你講個事
Okay, let me tell you a story.
96年時候
It was ninety-six.
我在太空已經待了42天
I'd been up here for forty-two days.
每次路過德克薩斯  都會俯視地球
Every time I passed over Texas, I looked down
以為我太太也在仰望我  思念我
knowing that Mrs. Kowalski was looking up, thinking of me.
整整六周我都向那女人飛吻
Six weeks I was blowing kisses at that woman.
等我回到愛德華茲基地卻發現
Then we land at Edwards and I find out
她跟一個律師跑了
that she's run off with this lawyer.
-我把行李裝上車  去了...-提華納
- So, I packed my car, and I headed to... - Tijuana.
墨西哥西北部城市
這事你講過了  庫沃斯基
You've told this story, Kowalski.
休士頓記得
As Houston recalls,
她還開走了你那輛74年的GTO
she, uh, took off in your seventy-four GTO.
工程組詢問噴氣背包燃料狀況
Engineering requests fuel status on the jetpack prototype.
出艙5小時  顯示消耗30%
Five hours off the reservation and I show thirty percent drain.
請替我讚美工程組
Give my compliments to Engineering.
除滾軸重定有點小故障外
Except for a slight malfunction in the nulling of the roll axis,
這噴氣背包還真給力
this jetpack is one prime piece of thrust.
工程組說謝謝你
Engineering says thank you.
告訴他們我還是更喜歡
Tell 'em I still prefer
我那輛67年的克爾維特跑車
my sixty-seven Corvette, though.
說到這個  我有沒有講過...
Speaking of which, did I ever tell you...
大家都瞭解你跑車那事  馬特
We know the Corvette story, Matt.
工程組也瞭解嗎
Even Engineering?
他們最瞭解
Especially Engineering.
我們會想念你的  馬特
We're going to miss you, Matt.
-通信卡正在重啟  -謝謝你  博士
- Comms card reboot in progress. - Thank you, Doctor.
謝裡夫  你那怎麼樣
Shariff, what's your status?
差不多了  正在更換電池組件A1和C
Nearly there. Replacing battery module A-one and C.
能確定些嗎
Could you be a little more specific?
休士頓最怕這種模糊估計
Indeterminate estimates make Houston anxious.
休士頓  請不用擔心
No, no, no. Houston. Don't be anxious.
焦慮對心臟不好
Anxiety's not good for the heart.
系統已做好重啟準備
System is ready to reactivate.
哈勃望遠鏡已啟動  完成升級
Hubble telescope engaged. Upgrade fully functional.
掌聲是送給你的  謝裡夫
That applause you hear is for you, Shariff.
恭喜你  放鬆一下
Congratulations. Kick back,
今天可以好好休息了
take the rest of the day off.
馬特  你能看得到
Matt, do you have a visual on just
任務專員謝裡夫在搞什麼嗎
what Mission Specialist Shariff is doing up there?
他好像在跳某種慶祝舞
He appears to be doing some form of the Macarena.
我也只能猜出這些了
But that would be just a best-guess scenario on my part.
斯通博士  這是休士頓
Dr. Stone, Houston.
醫護組發現你體溫已降到35.9
Medical now have you with a temperature drop to
心率升到70了
thirty-five-point-nine and a heart-rate rise to seventy.
-你有什麼感覺  -休士頓  我很好
- How are you feeling? - Houston, I'm fine.
只是零重力下
It's just keeping your lunch down
讓午飯待在胃裡可不容易
in zero-G is harder than it looks.
斯通博士  醫護組問你要不要回探索者號
Dr. Stone, Medical is asking if you want to return to Explorer.
不用  我們都來一周了  休士頓
Negative. We're been here a week, Houston.
趕快弄完吧
Let's just finish this.
-通信卡已啟動  -通信失敗
- Card is up. - No, that's a negative.
這邊沒有顯示  博士
I'll afraid we're getting nothing on this end, Doctor.
-重試  -還是沒有
- Try again. - No, still nothing.
休士頓  能把音樂關掉嗎
Houston, can you please turn that music off?
庫沃斯基
Kowalski.
沒問題
Not a problem.
謝謝  庫沃斯基
Thank you, Kowalski.
-現在呢  -還是不行
- Now, Houston? - That's a negative.
是不是休士頓讀取資料有誤
Could Houston be misinterpreting the data?
我們沒有收到任何資料
Well, we're not receiving any data.
工程組建議目測一下元件是否受損
Engineering is recommending a vis-check for component damage.
我來看看
Let me see what's going on.
怎麼回事
What have we got?
目測未發現組件受損
Visual examination doesn't reveal any damaged components.
問題一定出在通信面板
The problem must be originating from the comms panel.
是的  看來如此
Yeah, that seems to be the case.
工程組承認你之前警告過這種可能
Engineering admits that you warned us that this could happen.
就當作他們的道歉吧
That's as close to an apology as you're going to get from them.
我們該聽取你的意見  博士
We should have listened to you, Doc.
-開始吧  -看來得臨場發揮了
- Get working. - Well, looks like we're going to have to improvise.
-在試了  -你覺得要多久
- I'm on it. - How long do you think it'll take you?
-一小時  -很好
- One hour. - Outstanding.
在哈勃望遠鏡裡
Installing your system
安裝你的系統  是本次任務的目標
in the Hubble is the purpose of this mission
感謝你的耐心工作  博士
and so we appreciate your patience, Doctor.
庫沃斯基  我們知道你不在意這個
Kowalski, we... we know you don't care about things like this,
也就告訴你一聲
but, uh, for your information,
這次延遲還是不足以讓你打破
this delay is not gonna be long enough
阿納托利•索洛維約夫的太空行走紀錄
for you to break Anatoly Solovyev's spacewalking record.
-看來還得有...-不就75分鐘嗎
- It seems like you're gonna be left... - Seventy-five minutes shy?
誰稀罕這個啊
Never crossed my mind.
馬特  和你合作真好
Matt... it's been a privilege.
彼此彼此  休士頓
Right back at you, Houston.
享受你最後一次太空行走吧
Enjoy your last walk.
我可以幫助斯通博士拆下通信板嗎
Am I a go to assist Dr. Stone in removing the panel?
-感謝幫助  -准許
- Assistance appreciated. - Permission granted.
謝謝  休士頓
Thank you, Houston.
-可以搭把手嗎  -當然
- Mind if I join the fun? - Certainly.
感覺怎麼樣
How you feeling?
就像吉娃娃被丟進甩幹桶
Like a Chihuahua that's being tumble-dried.
很難熬的一周
Well, it's been a rough week.
這麼說你可能感覺好點
If it makes you feel any better,
我第一次來太空時
I coughed up everything
差點把腎都吐出來
but my kidneys on my first ride.
糟糕
Shit.
不好意思
Sorry.
我更習慣在醫院的地下實驗室
I'll used to a basement lab in a hospital
東西都會掉在地上  謝謝
where things fall to the floor. Thank you.
你可是這裡的天才  我只是個開車的
Well, you're the genius up here. I only drive the bus.
別急著叫我天才
Yeah, well, call me a genius
先看我一小時能不能把面板初始化吧
if I can get this board initialized in the next hour.
探索者  我是休士頓
Explorer, this is Houston.
請講  休士頓
Go ahead, Houston.
北美防空司令部稱
NORAD reports
一顆俄羅斯衛星遭導彈攻擊
a Russian satellite has incurred a missile strike.
爆炸造成大量殘片
The impact has created a cloud of debris
正以時速兩萬英里運動
orbiting at twenty thousand miles per hour.
目前殘片與你方軌道無重疊
Current debris orbit does not overlap with your trajectory.
有情況會及時通知
We'll keep you posted on any developments.
收到  休士頓
Copy that, Houston.
我們...用擔心嗎
Should we... should we be worried?
不用  讓指揮中心擔心去吧
No, let's let the boys down there worry for us.
探索者  請將機械臂伸向酬載艙
Explorer, engage arm and pivot to cargo bay.
機械臂已就緒
Stand by for arm maneuver.
博士  給宇航局幹活
So, doc, now that you work for NASA,
覺得我們怎麼樣
how do you like us?
是不是像中頭彩了
Kind of like winning the lottery, huh?
我只是慶倖他們沒有削減我研究經費
I was just happy that they didn't cut the funding to my research.
-你訓練了多久  -六個月
- How long was your training? - Six months.
包括假期嗎
Including holidays?
這掃描系統做什麼的
So, what is this scanning system?
沒大用  馬特
Oh, nothing Matt.
只是瞭望宇宙邊緣的新眼睛
It's just a new set of eyes to scan the edge of the universe.
本來醫用的  但這是樣機
It's designed for hospital use, but this one's a prototype.
等待鎖合
Stand by for locking.
他們才不會為樣機提供經費
Listen, they don't bankroll prototypes.
哪怕你有湛藍迷人的眼睛
Even for your pretty blue eyes.
我眼睛棕色的
Well, my eyes are brown.
現在你眼睛是血紅色的
Right now, your eyes are bloodshot.
庫沃斯基
Kowalski!
我厲害吧
Is this great, or what?
就這還念過哈佛呢
And to think he went to Harvard.
不得不承認
You gotta admit one thing:
美輪美奐
can't beat the view.
你喜歡這裡的什麼
So, what do you like about being up here?
靜謐
The silence.
恐怕會喜歡上
I could get used to it.
真美
Terrific.
休士頓  初步看來  通信板已損壞
Houston, from first inspection, comms panel appears to be dead.
需要切換至輔助板嗎
Am I a go to cut link to auxiliary?
你是專家  博士  你定
You're the expert, doctor. It's your call.
休士頓  我對這次任務有種不祥的預感
Houston, I have a bad feeling about this mission.
-詳說  -感覺就像
- Please elaborate. - It's the same feeling
1987年的狂歡節
I had about Mardi Gras in 1987.
這個不錯
That is affirmative.
真沒想到
Surprisingly,
中心還沒過你狂歡節的故事
control hasn't heard the Mardi Gras story.
請繼續
Please proceed.
狂歡節第一天  我百轉千回開到波旁大街
Well, it's day one, and I'm bumping my way down Bourbon Street
尋找一個朋友的妹妹
looking for a sister of a friend of mine.
街上人山人海
Streets are full of people.
我想肯定找不到那女孩了
I'm thinking there's no way I'm  gonna find this girl.
-開始手控  -突然間
- Proceeding to override. - Then all of the sudden,
我一看  她就在那
I look up, and there she is,
我正要喊她  就看見她
and I'm about to yell out, and I see she's holding hands
手牽著一個毛茸茸的矮矬男
with some short, hairy guy
還穿著沙灘褲和花襯衫
in board shorts and a Margaritaville shirt.
然後我意識到那根本不是男的
And then I realize that this guy is not a guy.
那女孩兒正牽著一個...
That my girl is holding hands with a...
國際空間站  這是休士頓
ISS, this is Houston.
請講  休士頓
Proceed, Houston.
探索者  這是休士頓
Explorer, this is Houston.
請講  休士頓
Go ahead, Houston.
任務中止  重複  任務中止
Mission abort. Repeat. Mission abort.
立即撤離哈勃
Initiate emergency disconnect from Hubble.
開始返航
Begin reentry procedure.
國際空間站  啟動緊急撤離程式
ISS, initiate emergency evacuation.
收到  休士頓  馬上行動
Copy all, Houston, and in work.
馬特  立即返回探索者
Matt, immediate return to Explorer.
重複  立即回艙
Repeat, immediate return to Explorer.
收到
Copy.
探索者  準備開啟氣閘
Explorer, prep airlock.
氣閘就緒
Airlock engaged,
-可以進入  -休士頓  請明示
- ready to receive. - Houston, elaborate.
導彈擊中的殘片引起連鎖反應
Debris from the missile strike has caused a chain reaction,
撞擊到其他衛星  形成更多殘片
hitting other satellites and creating new debris.
正以超過子彈的速度
Traveling faster than a high-speed bullet
向你們的軌道飛去
up towards your altitude.
-是否收到  -收到
- All copy? - Copy all.
-關閉  斯通博士  -不行
- Put a bow on it, Dr. Stone. - I can't.
通信板正在初始化
The board is still initializing.
別讓我說第二遍
I'll not gonna ask you again.
-稍等  -不能等  快
- One second. - Not one second. Now.
關掉
Shut it down.
這是命令
That's an order.
對不起  真對不起
Okay, I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
好了  就好了
I'm done. I'm done.
庫沃斯基  請立即撤離哈勃
Kowalski, initiate emergency disconnect from the Hubble.
好吧  謝裡夫  我們走
All right, Shariff, let's do this.
收到  馬特
Roger, Matt.
休士頓  怎麼樣了
Houston, update.
已引起強烈連鎖反應
Well, we have a full-on chain reaction.
經證實  俄羅斯擊毀一枚己方衛星
It's been confirmed that it's the unintentional side effect
引發了意外後果
of the Russians striking one of their own satellites.
-他們打了自己的衛星  -人家自己事
- They shot down their own satellite? - Right of disposal.
可能是棄用的間諜衛星  這下變開花彈了
Most likely a spy sat gone bad. Now it's shrapnel.
探索者  準備脫離哈勃望遠鏡
Explorer, ready to disengage HST.
解鎖倒計時  3  2  1
Locks releasing in three... two... one.
探索者  有新資料
Explorer, new data coming through.
-什麼情況  休士頓  -不太妙
- What's the blowback, Houston? - It's not good.
大部分系統已癱瘓
Most of our systems are gone.
殘片連鎖反應失控並飛速擴散
Debris chain reaction is out of control and rapidly expanding.
多顆衛星受波及墜毀
Multiple satellites are down, and they keep on falling.
-多顆是指幾個  -基本都完了
- Define "Multiple satellites." - Most of them are gone.
通信系統也已癱瘓
Telecommunication systems are dead.
信號隨時可能中斷
Expect a communication blackout at any moment.
庫沃斯基  九點鐘方向發現殘片
Kowalski, visual of debris at nine o'clock.
半個北美都上不去臉書了
Half of North America just lost their Facebook.
探索者號  重複  通訊信號隨時可能
Explorer, repeat, expect a communication blackout
全面中斷
at any moment.
-收到  休斯頓  -探索者號  這裡是庫沃斯基
- Copy that, Houston. - Explorer, this is Kowalski,
目擊確認殘片飛來
confirming visual contact with debris.
-殘片來自某廣播衛星  -當心
- Debris is from a BSE sat. - Heads up!
-重複  我看到...-斯通博士請求快速返艙
- To repeat, I have... - Dr. Stone requesting faster transport.
我們得趕快撤離  快  快
We have to go. We have to go, go, go!
甘迺迪中心報告氣象條件不適宜返回地球
Kennedy reports meteorological conditions no-go for re-entry.
休斯頓  這裡是探索者號  請回復
Houston, Explorer. Copy.
探索者號  斯通博士請求快速返艙
Explorer, Dr. Stone requesting faster transport to bay area.
探索者號  聽到嗎
Explorer, do you copy?
探索者號  請求帶回斯通博士
Explorer, permission to retrieve Dr. Stone.
批准執行  庫沃斯基
You're a go, Kowalski.
休斯頓  這裡是探索者號  請回復
Houston, this is Explorer, copy.
-我來了  -休斯頓失去聯絡  休斯頓失去聯絡
- All right. - We've lost Houston. We're lost Houston.
-解開臍帶  我們得馬上撤離  -明白
- Unstrap. Look, we need to get the hell out of here. - All right.
馬特  要幫忙嗎
Need some help there, Matt?
-不  別等我們  -卡住了
- No, don't wait for us. - It's stuck!
-人員傷亡  人員傷亡  -休斯頓  這裡是探索者號  請回復
- Man down! Man down! - Houston, this is Explorer, copy.
休斯頓  這裡是探索者號  請回復  庫沃斯基  報...
Houston, this is Explorer, copy. Kowalski, repor...
探索者號被撞擊  探索者號  聽到嗎
Explorer's been hit! Explorer, do you read?
探索者號  探索者
Explorer! Explorer!
宇航員和機體脫離  斯通博士脫離
Astronaut is off structure! Dr. Stone is off structure!
-斯通博士  解開搭扣  -不
- Dr. Stone, detach! - No!
你必須解開
You must detach!
再不解開會被機械臂帶走
If you don't detach, that arm's gonna carry you too far!
聽我說  集中精神
Listen to my voice! You need to focus!
我快看不到你了
I'm losing visual of you.
再過一會兒我就找不到你了
In a few seconds, I won't be able to track you.
快解開搭扣  看不見你了
You need to detach! I can't see you anymore!
-快動手  -我在弄  正在弄
- Do it now! - I'll trying! I'll trying! I'll trying!
休斯頓  斯通博士脫離視野範圍
Houston, I've lost visual of Dr. Stone.
斯通博士  聽到嗎  重複  聽到嗎
Dr. Stone, do you copy? Repeat, do you copy?
-能  能聽到  我解開了  -報告位置
- Yes, yes, yes. I copy! I'm detached! - Give me your position.
我不知道  不知道  我在旋轉  沒辦法  沒辦...
I don't know! I don't know! I'll spinning! I can't... I can't...
-報告位置  -GPS失靈  無法使用
- Report your position. - GPS is down. It's down, I can't...
-報告視野  -跟你說了不知道  什麼都看不見
- Give me a visual. - I told you, nothing. I see nothing!
能看見探索者號嗎
Do you have a visual of Explorer?
-不能  -國際空間站呢  -看不見
- No. No. - Do you have a visual of ISS? - No.
集中精神
You need to focus.
什麼都行  太陽  地球  給我一個參照物
Anything, use the sun and the Earth, give me coordinates.
-我喘不過氣了  -快給我參照物
- I can't breathe! I can't breathe! - Give me coordinates!
斯通博士  聽到嗎
Dr. Stone, do you copy?
重複  能聽到嗎
Repeat, do you copy?
報告位置  快報告你的位置
Give me your position! Report your position.
你能否看見探索者號
Do you have a visual of Explorer?
或者國際空間站
Do you have a visual of ISS?
請集中精神  任何參照物都行
I need you to focus. Anything.
太陽或者地球  請報告參照物
Use the sun and the Earth, give me coordinates.
報告參照物
Give me coordinates.
庫沃斯基  庫沃斯基  聽到嗎
Kowalski? Kowalski, do you copy?
庫沃斯基  我...庫沃斯基  我看到了
Kowalski... I have... have a vis... Kowalski, I have a visual.
視野範圍內...可見探索者號
I have... have a visual of Explorer.
在我的北...正北方向
With north at... twelve o'clock
太空艙位於我和探索者號的中點
and the shuttle is at the center of the dial.
還能看到...中國空間站
I can see... I can see the Chinese station.
不對  是國際空間站
No, it's the International Space Station.
空間站位於
ISS is at...
我七點鐘方向
ISS is at seven o'clock.
庫沃斯基中尉  能聽到嗎
Lieutenant Kowalski, do you copy?
探索者號  能...能聽到嗎
Explorer, do you... do you copy?
休斯頓  能聽到嗎
Houston, do you copy?
休斯頓  這裡是任務專員萊恩•斯通
Houston, this is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone.
我已脫離船體  正在飄浮
I am off structure and I am drifting.
請回復
Do you copy?
聽到嗎
Anyone?
有人聽到嗎
Anybody?
有人在嗎
Do you copy?
請求回復
Please copy.
拜託了
Please.
-斯通博士  聽到嗎  -能  庫沃斯基中尉  聽到了
- Dr. Stone, do you copy? - Yeah, Lieutenant Kowalski, yes.
喂喂  庫沃斯基中尉  我在這兒
Yes, Lieutenant Kowalski, I'm here,
-在這兒  -重複  聽到嗎
- I'm here. - Repeat, do you copy?
-聽到  我在這兒  這兒啊  -快閃燈
- Yes, yes, I copy, I'm here! I'm here. - Flash your light.
-燈  什麼燈  -閃燈讓我看到你
- My light... my light? - Flash it so I can see you.
好的
Okay. Uh...
我的燈
I...
-閃了  我在閃  這裡這裡  -看到你了
- Okay, okay. Here, here! I'll here! - There you are.
保持閃爍  報告狀態
Hang on tight. Report your status.
沒事  沒事  我很好
I'll fine, I'll fine. I'll all right.
報告你的狀態  體征數值
Your status. Give me your readings.
PSI指"磅/平方吋"  太空服健康內壓應不大於4.3
PSI數值是3...3.6
Three... three... three point six PSI.
剩餘氧量  氧量還有多少
Your O2, give me your O2.
在下降  下降很快
Oxygen is going down. It's going down fast.
非常快  9
It's going down fast. Nine...
不  只有8%了
No. No, eight-eight percent.
-你呼吸太急促  -8  降到8%了
- Okay, you're breathing too fast. - Eight... it's going down eight percent.
你耗氧太快  得減緩
You're burning oxygen, and we don't want to do that.
-放輕鬆明白嗎  -抱歉  明白了
- We want to relax. Copy? - Okay, sorry. Yes, copy, copy.
-離你很近了  -請快點
- All right. Nearly there. - Please hurry.
-燈可以插好了  斯通博士  -抱歉  抱歉
- You can holster that torch, Dr. Stone. - Sorry. Sorry.
抓住你了  好嘞  我得把你拴上
Gotcha. All right, now I'll gonna tether you to me.
沒發現我其實這麼玉樹臨風瀟灑帥氣吧
I know, you never realized how devastatingly good-looking I am.
別盯著我看了  搭把手讓我把你拴起來
But I need you to stop staring and help me with the tether.
-明白了嗎  -明白  明白
- Okay? - Okay, okay.
明白了
I got it.
好  這就行了
All right, here we go. All right.
為了避免你被氣噴到
Now, to clear you from the jets...
得把你推開一段距離
I'll gonna give you a little push.
-別  不要  -我不使勁
- No, no, no, no. No, no, no. - Not a push.
-別  別推  -輕輕一下
- No, no. - A nudge.
別  別  不要啊  混蛋  別推  別推我
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no! Damn it, no! No!
瞧  丟不了你吧
See? Where you go, I go.
好多了
Better.
撤離吧
Let's get outta here.
-真是該死  -我理解你的心情
- Goddamn it. - I know what you mean.
-該死  -你耗氧又快了
- Damn it. - You're burning oxygen.
先返回太空艙如何  請回復
We're going back to the shuttle. How's that for a plan? Copy?
-操  -好滴  收到
- Fuck! - Right. Copy that.
休斯頓  能否通聯  這裡是庫沃斯基
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
斯通博士和我準備返回基地
Dr. Stone and I are gonna make our way back to base.
請求探索者號打開氣閘  能聽到嗎
Can you get the Explorer to prepare the airlock for arrival? Copy?
休斯頓  這裡是庫沃斯基  能否聽到
Houston, this is... Kowalski. How do you copy?
休斯頓  能否通聯  這裡是庫沃斯基
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
-他們聽不到的  -這可說不準
- They can't hear us. - We don't know that.
所以要不斷嘗試
That's why we keep talking.
萬一有人收到信號  你就能得救
If somebody is listening, they might just save your life.
-設置倒計時90分鐘  -為什麼是90
- Set your watch for ninety minutes. - Why ninety?
休斯頓測出
Well, Houston clocked
殘片時速為5萬英里
that debris at fifty thousand miles an hour.
以我們現處的軌道計算
If you factor in our current orbit,
大約再過90分鐘
then I figure we got about ninety minutes
就會再次遭到殘片襲擊
before we get our asses kicked again.
-氧氣含量降到6%了  -收到
- O2 down to six percent. - Okay.
沒了臍帶飄在太空很嚇人吧
Pretty scary shit being untethered up here, isn't it?
-沒錯  嚇到死  -你表現很出色
- Yeah, pretty scary shit. - Well, you did all right.
其實你也不賴
Well, you weren't so bad yourself.
休斯頓  能否通聯  這裡是庫沃斯基
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
我們當前位置大約
Our current location is approximately
距離探索者號900米
nine hundred meters out from the Explorer.
斯通博士和我準備
Dr. Stone and I would like to
搜尋任務專員謝裡夫的遺體
retrieve the body of Mission Specialist Shariff
帶回太空艙  可以執行嗎
and return it to the shuttle. Am I a go to retrieve?
-收到  -他在哪兒
- Roger that. - Where is he? Where is he?
天啊  天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
抓住他
Grab him!
-快抓住他  -我在抓  在抓
- Grab him! - I'll trying, I'll trying!
-你把我帶開了  -抓...抓著他了
- You're pulling me away. - Got... I got him!
像情人那樣抱住他
Clutch him like he's your Valentine.
抓住了  抓住他了
I got him. Okay. I got him.
你們這麼晃蕩我沒法推進
I can't engage my thrust with you two yo-yoing around.
上帝啊
Jesus Christ.
希望你們買夠了保險  休斯頓
Here's hoping you have a hell of an insurance policy, Houston.
探索者號毀壞十分嚴重
The damages to Explorer are catastrophic.
準備搜尋倖存者
Will commence search for survivors.
氧量降至5%
O2 down to five percent.
要撞上了  當心艙沿
All right, here we go. Careful of the edges!
抓住我
Here. Here!
休斯頓  能否通聯  請確認
Houston, in the blind. To confirm.
任務專員斯通博士
Mission Specialist Dr. Stone
以及任務指揮官馬修•庫沃斯基
and Mission Commander Matthew Kowalski
是STS-157僅有的倖存者
are the sole survivors of the STS-one-five-seven.
之前沒聽你的很抱歉
I apologize for not complying.
你下令時我就該放手的
I should're stopped working as soon as you instructed me to.
我們終究躲不過殘片撞擊
We were gonna get hit no matter what.
你怎麼做都無濟於事
There was nothing you could do to change that.
嘿
Hey.
怎麼
Yes?
我們得想辦法去空間站
All right, we have to make our way to the Space Station.
那邊
Over there.
這路有點遠  但必須借助那邊的逃生艙
It's a bit of a hike, but we need to use their escape pod,
聯盟號  才能返回地球
the Soyuz, to get back to Earth.
可以嗎
Agreed?
斯通博士  行嗎
Dr. Stone, agreed?
-好的  -請吧
- Agreed. - All right. After you.
天啊
Oh, God.
休斯頓  能否通聯  這裡是庫沃斯基
Houston, in the blind. This is Kowalski.
斯通博士和我決定前往國際空間站
Dr. Stone and I have determined to proceed to ISS
利用聯盟號飛船重返地球
and use one of their Soyuz for re-entry.
空間站  能收到嗎
ISS, if you hear us...
我們亟需救援
we could sure use a rescue mission.
-氧量2%了  -快到了
- O2 down to two percent. - We're getting there.
很美  你覺得呢
Beautiful, don't you think?
什麼
What?
日出
The sunrise.
最懷念這個了
That's what I'll gonna miss the most.
你哪兒的人  斯通博士
So where's home, Dr. Stone?
萊恩  你家在哪兒
Ryan, where's home?
家
Home?
下面  地球那個家
Down there. Mother Earth.
你住哪兒
Where do you pitch you tent?
-蘇黎世湖區  -那是什麼地方
- Lake Zurich. - Where the hell is that?
-伊利諾斯州  -伊州啊
- Illinois. - Illinois.
中部時區
Central Time Zone.
那就差不多是晚上
That would make it roughly...
八點樣子
eight PM.
那邊人們晚上八點都幹嘛呢
What are the good people of Lake Zurich doing at eight o'clock?
不知道
I don't know.
我過不去了  會拖累你的
I'm not gonna make it. I'm slowing you down.
你平時這會兒都幹嘛
What would you be doing?
跟我說說  萊恩  八點鐘
Come on, Ryan. It's eight o'clock.
是不是醫院18小時的班終於結束了
You've just left the hospital after an eighteen-hour shift.
開車回家
Driving home.
廣播
The radio.
-我在聽廣播  -這就對了
- I listen to the radio. - There we go.
我猜猜
Let me guess.
聽國廣  古典音樂  還是爬行榜
NPR? Classical? Top forty?
無所謂  只要主持人不廢話  我只管開車
Anything. I don't care, as long as they don't talk. I just drive.
開車去哪兒呢
And where are you driving to?
-就是開車而已  -下面有你想念的東西嗎
- I just drive. - What do you miss down there?
結婚了嗎
Is there a Mr. Stone?
-沒  -沒特別的人嗎
- No. - Nobody special?
沒人在地球上仰望天空  想著你嗎
Somebody down there looking up, thinking about you?
萊恩
Ryan?
我曾有個女兒
I had a daughter.
那年她四歲
She was four.
在學校捉迷藏
She was at school playing tag.
滑倒撞了頭  就走了
Slipped, hit her head, and that was it.
不堪回首
Stupidest thing.
我開車時接的電話
I was driving when I got the call, so...
從那以後  我就成這樣了
Ever since then, that's what I do.
起床
I wake up,
上班
I go to work,
開車
and I just drive.
氧氣降到1%了
O2 down to one percent.
我有個好消息  有個壞消息
Well, I've got good news and bad news.
好消息是五分鐘就到空間站
The good news is, we're about five minutes from the ISS
我還知道老俄的伏特加藏在哪裡
and I know where the Russians stash their vodka.
真好  我正缺杯酒提提神呢
And that is good, because I'm running on fumes here.
壞消息是  我還差十分鐘
The bad news is, I'm gonna be
就打破阿納托利的紀錄了
about ten minutes short of breaking Anatoly's record,
俄太空行走紀錄保持者
而我
and I...
-怎麼了  -我這裡報警了
- What? - I'm redlining.
氧壓不夠
My O2 tank pressure is low.
氧氣罐裡沒有了
Your tank is out of oxygen
-但太空服裡還有  -好吧
- but you still have it in your suit. - Got it.
慢慢呼吸  不要大口喘氣
So you have to sip, not gulp.
氧氣含量低
當喝紅酒  不是啤酒
Wine, not beer.
慢慢抿  萊恩
Sip, Ryan.
休士頓  能否通聯  我們已看到空間站
Houston, in the blind, we have a visual of the ISS.
但人員肯定已撤離
The station must have been evacuated
因為聯盟一號不見了
because the first Soyuz is missing.
聯盟二號的表面嚴重受損
The second Soyuz exhibits surface damage,
減速傘也打開了
and its chute has been deployed.
無法用作返回逃生艙
Any use as an escape pod for re-entry is impossible.
該變向了吧  又在漂了
Shouldn't we be turning? We're drifting again.
還不行  推進氣體我可沒開玩笑
Not yet. I wasn't kidding about those fumes.
這罐還夠我們噴它一兩次
This can has one or two good thrusts left...
如果走運的話
if we're lucky.
穩住
Steady.
看准
Aim.
噴射
Fire!
-減速  快減速  -不行  氣罐空了
Brake! Brake! You have to brake! - I can't, the can's empty.
會狠狠撞上去  能抓什麼就抓什麼
We're gonna hit hard! Grab a hold of anything you can!
怎麼辦  我該怎麼辦
What do I do? What do I do?!
萊恩
Ryan!
連接索斷裂  我脫離了  脫離了
The tether broke, I'm detached! I'm detached!
快抓東西
Grab a hold!
隨便抓個東西
Grab anything!
萊恩
Ryan!
-伸手  -會抓住你的
- Give me five! - I've got you.
一定能抓住  這裡  這邊啊
I've got you. Right here, right here.
-媽的  -不  不要
- Shit! - No. No, no, no
抓到了
Got ya.
謝天謝地
堅持住  我拉你過來
You just... hold on and I'm gonna start pulling you in.
-我要拉了  -博士
- I'm gonna start... - Hey, Doc.
堅持住  堅持  我會拉你回來的
Just hold on. Hang on. I am gonna pull you in.
-萊恩  聽我說  -我要拉了
- Ryan, listen. - I'll gonna pull you in.
你必須放手
You have to let me go.
繩子不行  會把你帶過來的
The ropes are too loose. I'll pulling you with me.
你必須鬆手  不然我們都會死
You have to let me go, or we both die.
我不會放開你的  我們可以
I'll not letting you go! We're fine!
萊恩  放開我吧
Ryan, let me go.
你哪裡也不能去  哪裡都不能去
You're not going anywhere. You're not going anywhere.
-你說了不算  -不  不要  別這樣
- It's not up to you. - No, no, no, no... Please don't do this.
求你了  拜託你  不要這樣做
Please, please, please, please don't do this.
求你別這樣啊  不  不要啊
Please don't do this. No, no, no.
別這樣  馬特  不要這樣做
Please don't, Matt. Please don't do this.
你會回去的  萊恩
You're gonna make it, Ryan.
不要啊
No.
我都抓住你了  都抓住了啊
I had you. I had you! I had you.
萊恩  能聽到嗎
Ryan, do you hear me?
-收到請回  -我的二氧化碳報警了
- Do you copy? - My CO2 alarm went off.
二氧化碳濃度報警
My CO2 alarm went off.
聽著  你要進入空間站
Look, you need to board the station.
看到氣閘了嗎
Do you see the airlock?
萊恩  收到嗎
Hey, Ryan, you copy?
先找到氣閘
Look for the airlock.
在你上方  曙光艙旁邊
It's above you, next to the Zarya module.
國際空間站一功能艙
看到了嗎
You see it?
我看到了  看到了
Yes, yes, I see it. I see it.
很好  你就是要去那裡
Good. That's where you want to go.
感覺現在有點頭暈吧
Now you're getting lightheaded, right?
-對  -因為你在吸入二氧化碳
- Yes. - That's because you're breathing CO2.
正在失去意識
You're losing consciousness.
現在必須進入空間站
You need to board the station.
聯盟二號受損嚴重  無法返回地球
That second Soyuz is too damaged for re-entry,
不過開著玩玩很不錯
but it's perfectly fine for a little Sunday drive.
開著玩玩
Sunday drive?
往西邊看  看到遠處那個亮點了嗎
Look to the west. You see that dot in the distance?
-看到了  -那是中國空間站
- Yes. - That's a Chinese station.
你要開著聯盟號溜達到那裡
You're gonna take the Soyuz, and you're gonna cruise over there.
中方救生艙叫神舟
Chinese lifeboat is a Shenzhou.
-我可沒碰過神舟  -沒關係
- I've never flown a Shenzhou. - It doesn't matter.
返地規程和聯盟號一樣
Its re-entry protocol is identical to the Soyuz.
-聯盟號也沒開過嗎  -就上過模擬器
- You never flown the Soyuz either? - Only a simulator.
那就行
Well, then you know.
可我墜毀了
But I crashed it.
模擬器可不就用來撞毀嘛
It's a simulator, that's what it's designed for.
可是  我每次都墜毀
Every time. I crashed it every time.
把那玩意對準地球就行了
You point the damn thing at Earth.
一點不複雜
It's not rocket science.
明天這個時候
And by this time tomorrow,
你就能回到蘇黎世湖
you're gonna be back in Lake Zurich
跟他們講這番驚心動魄了
with a hell of a story to tell.
能收到嗎
You copy?
萊恩  收到嗎
Ryan, you copy?
我要駕駛聯盟號去找你
I'm gonna take the Soyuz and come get you.
-不行  -我要去接你
- No, you're not. - I'm coming to get you.
我已經離你太遠了
No, I've got too much of a head start on you.
我會去救你的
I'm coming to get you.
你這趟車我真趕不上了
I'm afraid that ship already sailed.
萊恩  你要學會放手
Ryan, you're gonna have to learn to let go.
-但我...-我想聽你說  你可以回去
- But I... - I want to hear you say you're gonna make it...
快  萊恩  說給我聽
Come on, Ryan, say it.
-我可以回去  -真乖  繼續前行
- I'm gonna make it. - All right. Keep going.
女孩子家怎麼叫萊恩呢
What kind of name is Ryan for a girl?
我爸爸想要個男孩
Dad wanted a boy.
到氣閘了嗎
Are you close to the airlock?
-還沒  -那繼續
- Not yet. - Keep going.
現在你我也算保持了一定距離
So now that we have some distance between us.
-你喜歡我對吧  -什麼
- You're attracted to me, right? - What?
大家都說我有雙迷人的藍眼睛
Well, people say I have beautiful blue eyes.
你的確有一雙...迷人的藍眼睛
You have beautiful... you have beautiful blue eyes.
我眼睛是棕色的
I have brown eyes.
-想聽好消息嗎  -什麼
- You want to know the good news? - What?
我要打破阿納托利的紀錄了
I'm gonna break Anatoly's record,
而且這紀錄可能得保持很久
and I think mine's gonna stand for a long, long time.
不  我會去救你
No. I'm coming to get you.
-天啊  -怎麼了
- Oh, my God. - What? What?
-萊恩  -什麼
- Hey, Ryan? - Yeah?
你該看看陽光灑在恒河的美景
You should see the sun on the Ganges.
太震撼了
It's amazing.
在哪呢  到底在哪裡
Where are you? Where are you?
通信室  通信室  終於找到你了
Comms. Comms. There you are. Okay.
馬特  我是萊恩  收到回話
Matt, this is Ryan, copy.
馬特  我是萊恩  收到請回
馬特  我到空間站了  能收到嗎
Matt, I made it, I'm here, I'm on the station. Do you copy?
馬特  快回答我
Come on, Matt, talk to me.
你在哪裡  報告你的位置
Tell me where you are, give me your position.
你在哪裡  視野  報告你的視野
Where are you? Give me a visual. Just tell me what you see.
離開卡納維拉爾角後  你不是話很多嗎
Come on. You've been yammering since we left Cape Canaveral,
現在怎麼不出聲了
and now you decide to shut up?
快說句話  什麼都可以  什麼都行
Talk to me. Just say something, say anything! I don't care!
跟我說說狂歡節的事
Hey, tell me about, uh, Mardi Gras.
跟我說說那個毛茸茸的矬男
Tell me about the hairy guy. Huh?
給我講講下文
Tell me what happened.
那毛茸矬男最後怎麼了
What happened to the hairy guy?
快回答我啊
Please talk to me.
求你了
Please.
休士頓  能否通聯
Houston, in the blind...
這裡是任務專員萊恩•斯通
this is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone
從國際空間站呼叫
reporting from the ISS.
與任務指揮官馬修•庫沃斯基
All communications with Mission Commander Matthew Kowalski
通信徹底中斷
have been lost.
無線電通信已中斷
Radio transmission absent.
視野範圍均不可見
Visuals nonexistent.
請求確認
To confirm,
本人萊恩•斯通
I, Ryan Stone, am the sole survivor
STS-157唯一倖存者
of STS-one-five-seven.
又怎麼了
What now?
火警
在哪呢  動力開關在哪呢
Okay. Where is it, where is it? Where is the power?
是這個了
Here you are.
很好  像訓練時那樣  分離船艙
Great, just like training. Undocking, undocking.
離艙手冊  紅色
Undocking. Red.
在哪呢  在哪呢
Okay, where is it? Where is it?
快啊
Come on.
很好  這個我記得  我記得
Okay, I remember this, I remember this.
不夠四分鐘了
You don't have four minutes.
得人工作業
We're going manual.
快啊
Come on.
有了  啟動  脫離
Okay. Active-Activate, undock.
七分鐘逃離這裡
Seven minutes to get out of here.
好了  開始吧
All right, okay.
這又怎麼了
What... what?
不  不要  不要啊
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no!
停  停  停下來
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
這就對了
That's right, that's right.
慢慢來  慢慢來
Come on, Come on, Come on.
對  這就對了
That's right, that's right, that's right.
來吧
Come on.
這下好了
Great.
晴空萬里  有可能碰上衛星殘片
Clear skies with a chance of satellite debris.
先弄開  然後回家  小菜一碟
Okay, we detach this, and we go home. Piece of cake.
怎麼做呢
Okay, what do we have?
就它了
Okay, all right.
該死
Shit.
得趕緊了
Okay, come on.
快  快
Come on, come on.
好了
All right.
我討厭太空
I hate space.
別叫了
Shut up.
終於好了
That's good.
要穩住啊
Let's stabilize you.
不錯
Okay.
咱們去逛逛中國站
Let's go visit the Chinese station.
休士頓  能否通聯
Houston, in the blind,
天宮一號位於西側100公里附近
Tiangong is approximately one hundred kilometers to the west,
我偏離了約13度
and I am off its course by about thirteen degrees.
即將修正軌道
I will correct trajectory.
好了
Okay.
準備與SKD對接
I will engage S-Ka-Dae in
5  4  3  2  1
five... four... three... two... one.
又發生什麼事了
What's happening, what's happening? Come on, come on.
啟動啊  啟動啊
Come on, come on.
開什麼玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
不要開玩笑啊
You gotta be kidding me!
你去死吧
No! Don't you fuck...
休斯頓  能否通聯
Houston, in the blind.
休斯頓  能否通聯  這裡萊恩•斯通博士
Houston, in the blind, this is Dr. Ryan Stone.
從聯盟TMA-14M號呼叫
I'm calling from the Soyuz TMA-one-four-M.
飛船燃料耗盡  飄浮中  收到嗎
I'm currently out of fuel and adrift, do you copy?
休斯頓  我是萊恩•斯通博士
Houston. This is Dr. Ryan Stone.
收到嗎
Do you copy?
休斯頓  我是萊恩•斯通  收到嗎
Houston. This is Ryan Stone. Do you copy?
休斯頓  我是...
Houston, this is Mission...
我是航太任務專員萊恩•斯通  收到嗎
Mission Specialist Ryan Stone, do you copy?
休斯頓  休斯頓  請確認身份
Houston, Houston, please confirm identity.
休斯頓  調幅波段收到你的回應  請講話
Houston, you're coming in over an AM Frequency. Copy.
收到嗎
Do you copy?
你是中國站天宮一號嗎  完畢
Is this the Chinese station? Is this Tiangong? Copy.
求救  收到嗎  求救  緊急求救
Mayday, can you copy? Mayday, mayday, mayday.
是的  求救  求救
Yes, yes. Mayday, mayday. Mayday, mayday.
安寧剛
Aningaaq.
那是...是你的名字嗎
Is that... is that your... is that your name?
安寧剛是你的名字嗎  你叫這個嗎
Aningaaq is your... is your name? Is that your name?
梅迪
Mayday!
不  不  我不叫梅迪  我叫斯通
No, no, no. No, my name is not Mayday. I'm Stone.
我是萊恩•斯通博士  需要救援
Dr. Ryan Stone, I need help. I am...
狗叫聲
Those are dogs.
地球信號
They're calling from Earth.
是地球的信號
安寧剛  能讓狗狗再叫幾聲嗎  可以嗎
Aningaaq, make your dogs bark again for me, would you please?
狗狗  狗叫聲  汪汪  狗狗
Your dogs. Dogs, you know. Woof, woof. Dogs.
我快要死了  安寧剛
Oh, I'm gonna die, Aningaaq.
大家知道  人總有一死
I know, we're all gonna die. Everybody knows that.
但我今天就要死了
But I'm gonna die today.
挺搞笑吧  但...
Funny, that. You know, to know...
但我很害怕
but the thing is, it's that I'm still scared.
非常非常怕
I'm really scared.
沒人會悼念我
Nobody will mourn for me,
沒人會為我祈禱了
no one will pray for my soul.
你會嗎
Will you mourn for me?
你會為我祈禱嗎
Will you say a prayer for me?
會不會太晚了
Or is it too late?
我想為自己祈禱  但從沒祈禱過
I mean, I'd say one for myself, but I'm never prayed in my life,
而且
so...
從來沒人教過我如何祈禱
Nobody ever taught me how.
是寶寶
A baby.
你抱著寶寶  是嗎
There's a baby with you, huh?
你在唱搖籃曲嗎
Is that a lullaby you're singing?
好溫馨啊
That's so sweet.
我以前也常唱給寶寶聽
I used to sing to my baby.
馬上就能見到她了
I hope I see her soon.
氧氣
很好聽  安寧剛  別停  唱下去
That's nice, Aningaaq. Keep singing, just like that.
唱到我睡著  讓我睡去吧
Sing me to sleep, and I'll sleep.
別停  繼續  繼續
Keep singing. And sing, and sing.
不  不要
No, no, don't!
看看表  13小時11分鐘
Check your watch. Thirteen hours and eleven minutes.
告訴阿納托利  我破他紀錄了
Call Anatoly and tell him he's been bumped.
-這裡挺暗的  -你怎麼...
- It's a little gloomy in here, isn't it? - How did you...?
-相信我  一言難盡  -你怎麼...
- Trust me, it's a hell of a story. - But how did...?
這樣好多了
That's better.
我找到一塊備用電池
I found a little extra... a little extra battery power.
還好你沒在邊上分散我注意力
It helps that I didn't have you around to distract me.
不得不說  很高興再見到你
I have to say, I'm glad to see ya.
我以為你早去天堂了呢
I didn't think you were gonna make it.
-找到伏特加了嗎  -你...
- Did you find the vodka? - You...
你沒有告訴我藏哪了
You never told me where... where it was, so...
敬阿納托利  乾杯[波蘭語]
To Anatoly. Na zdorovje.
-不了  -不嗎  那算了
- No. - No? All right.
我們離開這鬼地方吧
Let's get out of here.
中國站離著大約100英里
The Chinese station's about a hundred miles.
咱們來個陽光之旅吧
Just a little Sunday drive.
-飛不了了  -飛的了
- We can't. - Sure we can.
沒燃料了  都試過了
There's no fuel, I tried everything.
-總有能派上用場的  -什麼都用不了
- Well, there's always something we can do. - I tried everything.
軟著陸推進你沒試吧
Did you try the soft landing jets?
-那個著陸才用的到  -著陸也要推進呢
- They're for landing. So... - Well, landing is launching.
反正都一樣  訓練課沒教嗎
It's the same thing. Didn't you learn about that in training?
都告訴過你  模擬器我都沒成功著陸過
I never got to land the simulator. I told you that.
-但你知道操作  -我每次都墜毀
- But you know about it. - And I crashed it every time.
那你是想回家還是想待在這
Listen, do you want to go back, or do you want to stay here?
我懂了  太空很漂亮
I get it, it's nice up here.
你可以關掉所有系統
You can just shut down all the systems,
關掉所有燈光
turn out all the lights...
閉上眼睛  忽略世人
and just close your eyes and tune out everybody.
在太空沒人可以傷害你
There's nobody up here that can hurt you.
很安全
It's safe.
為什麼要堅持  為什麼要活下去
I mean, what's the point of going on? What's the point of living?
有什麼能比孩子的死還痛呢
Your kid died. Doesn't get any rougher than that.
關鍵看你現在怎麼做
But still, it's a matter of what you do now.
若決定回去  那就行動起來
If you decide to go, then you gotta just get on with it.
坐穩扶好  享受旅程
Sit back, enjoy the ride.
你要站在地球上
You gotta plant both your feet on the ground
開始新生活
and start livin' life.
-你怎麼回來的  -說過了  一言難盡
- How did you get here? - I'll telling you, it's a hell of a story.
-萊恩  -怎麼了
- Hey, Ryan? - What?
該回家了
It's time to go home.
氧氣
著陸
Landing...
著陸  著陸也可以推進
Landing... landing is launching.
我還說...
I said...
對  著陸  著陸手冊是綠色的
Okay, landing, landing. Landing is green.
沒錯  就這本
Okay, landing. All right.
軟著陸推進器開關
Okay. Soft landing jets trigger
會在距地面三米自動開啟
automatically at three meters before landing, so...
馬特  你他媽可真聰明
You're a clever son of a bitch, Matt.
我需要...需要讓軌道艙
I need to... I need to get rid of the B.O...
與推進器分離
and the engine module.
對  沒錯
Right. Okay.
來吧
Okay.
三艙分離
Tri-module separation.
啟動
Go.
好了
Okay.
休斯頓  到最棘手的部分了
Houston, here's the tricky part.
得讓聯盟號認為
Soyuz has to think
我們距地面已是三米
we are three meters off the Earth.
好吧
All right. Okay.
馬特  看在這周
Hey, Matt? Since I had to listen
聽你嘮叨的份上
to endless hours of your storytelling this week,
給你個機會幫幫我
I need for you to do me a favor.
你將會看到一個棕發女孩
You are gonna see a little girl with brown hair,
頭髮像個鳥窩
very messy, lots of knots.
她不喜歡梳頭  沒關係的
She doesn't like to brush it. That's okay.
她叫薩拉
Her name is Sarah.
能拜託你轉告她嗎
Can you please tell her
告訴她  媽媽找到她紅鞋子了
that Mama found her red shoe?
馬特  她總是惦記那只鞋子
She was so worried about that shoe, Matt.
其實就在床底下
But it was just right under the bed.
替我好好抱抱她  親親她
Give her a big hug and a big kiss for me,
告訴她我想死她了
and tell her that Mama misses her.
她是我的心肝寶貝
You tell her that she is my angel.
她讓我驕傲  特驕傲
And she makes me so proud. So, so proud.
告訴她我沒有放棄
And you tell her that I'm not quitting.
告訴她我很愛她
You tell her that I love her, Matt.
告訴她我很愛很愛她
You tell her that I love her so much.
這個忙能幫我嗎
Can you do that for me?
收到
Roger that.
啟程
Here we go.
天宮  你也在下降啊
You're losing altitude, Tiangong.
這麼下降就要和氣層激情四射了
You keep dropping and you're gonna kiss the atmosphere.
你是最後一班車  別丟下我
But not without me, because you're my last ride.
好吧
Okay.
等等
Wait.
不就開車嘛
No more just driving.
回家吧
Let's go home.
穩住  別晃  別晃
Steady. Okay, come on, come on.
穩住  穩住
Steady, steady.
別晃  別晃
Come on. Come on.
在哪呢  你在哪呢  四十五度
Where are you? Where are you? Forty-five,
九十度  背後  在背後
ninety, one-eighty, one-eighty.
加油
Come on.
就這樣
Okay.
就到了
All right.
媽的
Damn it.
近點  近點  媽媽抱
Down, down, down. Come to Mama.
媽的
Shit!
到了  神舟呢  神舟呢
Come on. Shenzhou, come on. Shenzhou. Shenzhou.
媽的  是這邊  神舟我來了
Fuck! Okay, this way. Shenzhou.
這是什麼
What's this?
聯盟號的動力開關在這裡
In the Soyuz, the power button is here.
好的  要脫離對接  脫離對接
Okay, undocking, undocking.
"咦呢  咪呢"
Eeni, meeni...
對  就是這個聲音 "麥呢  嚜"
Okay, that doesn't sound good. Miny... moe.
聽不懂中文
No hablo chino.
"麥呢  嚜"
Miny... moe.
對了  對了  太棒了
Okay. Okay, good.
休斯頓  休斯頓  能否通聯
Houston. Houston, in the blind.
我是航太任務專員萊恩•斯通
This is Mission Specialist Ryan Stone
正從神舟上呼叫你
reporting from the Shenzhou.
我馬上要脫開天宮一號了
I'll about to undock from Tiangong...
我對這次任務有不祥的預感
And I have a bad feeling about this mission.
讓我想起一個故事  休斯頓...
Reminds me of a story, Houston...
算了  休斯頓  不說了
Never... Never mind the story, Houston. Never mind the story.
這裡越來越熱了  會沒事的
It's getting hot in here. Okay. All right.
依我看來  只有兩個結果
All right, the way I see it, there's only two possible outcomes.
要麼安全降落
Either I make it down there in one piece
帶回一段傳奇經歷
and I have one hell of a story to tell,
要麼在十分鐘內化為灰燼
or I burn up in the next ten minutes.
管他哪種結果  一切隨緣
Either way, whichever way... no harm, no foul!
因為不管哪種結果
Because either way...
這段旅程都充滿意義
it'll be one hell of a ride.
我準備好了
I'm ready.
神舟  能否通聯  這裡是休斯頓
Shenzhou, in the blind, this is Houston.
請告知調頻波段
Indicate FM frequency.
雷達監測你處於返回軌道
Our radars detect you on a re-entry trajectory.
若能收到  請確認身份
If you copy, please confirm identity.
這裡是休斯頓[伴無線電干擾]
This is Houston.
沒錢
No money down!
-一切安好...-請立即表明身份
- ...messages, we'll be right... - Please confirm identity.
中西部天氣晴朗無雲
Skies over the Midwest are completely clear...
已部署救援隊前去搜救
We're deployed a rescue mission to retrieve you.
救援隊在途中
Rescue mission is on the way.
神舟  能否通聯  這裡是休斯頓
Shenzhou, in the blind, this is Houston.
已部署救援隊前去搜救
We're deployed a rescue mission to retrieve you.
謝謝你
Thank you.
沒事的
No.
地      心      引      力